(The drama was based on a book, and all people, organizations,)
(الدراما مبنية على كتاب، وكل الأشخاص والمنظمات،)
(locations, and incidents in this drama are fictitious.)
(المواقع والحوادث في هذه الدراما خيالية.)
(It was filmed in accordance with COVID-19 prevention guidelines.)
(تم تصويره وفقًا لإرشادات الوقاية من فيروس كورونا).
(The crime-related scenes were staged.)
(تم تمثيل مشاهد الجريمة).
(This drama may contain disturbing and brutal scenes.)
(قد تحتوي هذه الدراما على مشاهد مزعجة ووحشية).
Right before the Chuseok holidays...
قبل عطلة تشوسوك مباشرة..
I'm sorry I was late. There was heavy traffic.
أنا آسف لأنني تأخرت. كانت هناك حركة مرور كثيفة.
No, it's fine. You picked me up when I had just gotten out.
لا، لا بأس. لقد التقطتني عندما خرجت للتو.
Hey, my cousin got married pretty late.
مهلا، ابن عمي تزوج في وقت متأخر جدا.
So everyone at the wedding cried.
لذلك بكى الجميع في حفل الزفاف.
And my mother wanted to pack up some food from the buffet.
وأرادت والدتي أن تحزم بعض الطعام من البوفيه.
Look at all this food she packed for me. My goodness.
انظر إلى كل هذا الطعام الذي جهزته لي. يا إلهي.
This sure makes us feel like normal people, doesn't it?
هذا بالتأكيد يجعلنا نشعر وكأننا أشخاص عاديين، أليس كذلك؟
I went to a wedding on Saturday.
ذهبت لحضور حفل زفاف يوم السبت.
And we're stuck downtown in the middle of a congested road.
ونحن عالقون في وسط المدينة وسط طريق مزدحم.
It'd be perfect if only we weren't headed to a prison.
سيكون الأمر مثاليًا لو لم نكن متجهين إلى السجن.
Seoul Tollgate announced that cars leaving Seoul...
أعلنت شركة "سيول تولغيت" أن السيارات التي تغادر سيول...
Hey. How do office workers wear ties every day?
مهلا. كيف يرتدي موظفو المكاتب ربطات العنق كل يوم؟
This is so suffocating.
هذا خانق للغاية.
And the Honam Expressway...
وطريق هونام السريع...
Gosh. Maybe, I should have brought some clothes to change into.
يا إلهي. ربما كان علي أن أحضر بعض الملابس لأغير ملابسي.
Do you want to switch shoes at least?
هل تريد تبديل حذائك على الأقل؟
- No, it's okay. - By tonight...
- لا، لا بأس. - بحلول هذه الليلة...
- Do you want some rice cakes? - What?
- هل تريد بعض كعك الأرز؟ - ماذا؟
- Open your mouth. - I'm good.
- افتح فمك. - أنا بخير.
- Open up. - It's expected to take longer.
- افتح. - ومن المتوقع أن يستغرق وقتا أطول.
- There. Chew it. - Hello, everyone.
- هناك. مضغه. - أهلا بالجميع.
Yes. That's it.
نعم. هذا كل شيء.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
(Seoul Detention Center)
(مركز الاحتجاز في سيول)
- Gosh. Isn't it nice? - Gosh.
- يا إلهي. أليس لطيفا؟ - يا إلهي.
It does look big and nice.
أنها تبدو كبيرة وجميلة.
I spent two months' salary on this.
لقد أنفقت راتب شهرين على هذا.
It better look fancy.
من الأفضل أن تبدو فاخرة.
You're spending more than you're earning.
أنت تنفق أكثر مما تكسب.
You need the right tools to put your skills to use.
أنت بحاجة إلى الأدوات المناسبة لاستخدام مهاراتك.
Hey, this kind of looks lame.
مهلا، هذا النوع من يبدو عرجاء.
I'll put it away.
سوف أضعه بعيدا.
But I'm more comfortable with it. Let me use it.
لكنني أكثر راحة معها. اسمحوا لي أن استخدامه.
- You want to? - Yes.
- اتريد؟ - نعم.
- Okay, it's all yours. - Thank you.
- حسنًا، كل هذا لك. - شكرًا لك.
All right. Hold on.
حسنًا. يتمسك.
This should be...
يجب أن يكون هذا...
Should we put this here?
هل يجب أن نضع هذا هنا؟
(Keep quiet)
(التزم الصمت)
Inmate 4709, you have visitors.
النزيل 4709، لديك زوار.
Who's here?
من هنا؟
Look at him dusting off his feet again. Gosh.
انظر إليه وهو ينفض الغبار عن قدميه مرة أخرى. يا إلهي.
- That fool. - Just go, will you?
- ذلك الأحمق. - فقط اذهب، هل ستفعل؟
- Idiot. - Gosh, seriously.
- غبي. - يا إلهي، بجدية.
(Do not flush leftovers down the toilet.)
(لا ترمي بقايا الطعام في المرحاض.)
- Hurry up. The officer is waiting. - Goodness.
- أسرع. الضابط ينتظر. - الخير.
Gosh, that fool.
يا إلهي، هذا الأحمق.
- I'm sorry, man. - What? What the...
- أنا آسف يا رجل. - ماذا؟ ما...
You can't blindside me like this.
لا يمكنك أن تعمى لي مثل هذا.
I can't even stand the way he walks.
لا أستطيع حتى أن أتحمل الطريقة التي يمشي بها.
- Goodness. - That idiot.
- الخير. - ذلك الأحمق.
What's with him?
ماذا به؟
Well, we're not here to interrogate you, so relax.
حسنًا، نحن لسنا هنا لاستجوابك، لذا استرخي.
Did you put on a suit to meet me?
هل ارتديت بدلة لمقابلتي؟
Why do you ask?
لماذا تسأل؟
I feel special.
أشعر بأنني مميز.
But it's all over now, isn't it?
ولكن كل شيء انتهى الآن، أليس كذلك؟
Do you think it's over?
هل تعتقد أن الأمر قد انتهى؟
You caught me.
لقد أمسكت بي.
Mr. Cho, we still have...
سيد تشو، لا يزال لدينا...
many questions for you.
أسئلة كثيرة بالنسبة لك.
But I told you everything last time.
لكنني أخبرتك بكل شيء آخر مرة.
That lady too. I told her everything.
تلك السيدة أيضا. قلت لها كل شيء.
She is a detective, not a "lady."
إنها محققة وليست "سيدة".
We want to hear more about you, not about the case.
نريد أن نسمع المزيد عنك، وليس عن القضية.
You could tell us about your childhood...
ممكن تحكي لنا عن طفولتك..
or how you feel. Feel free to tell us anything.
أو كيف تشعر. لا تتردد في إخبارنا بأي شيء.
It's just for our record, so don't worry about it.
إنه فقط لسجلنا، لذلك لا تقلق بشأن ذلك.
Right.
يمين.
Well... Is there anything you'd like to tell us?
حسنًا... هل هناك أي شيء تريد إخبارنا به؟
It's okay. You can tell us anything.
لا بأس. يمكنك أن تقول لنا أي شيء.
You're not interrogating me, but you want to hear my story?
أنت لا تستجوبني، لكنك تريد سماع قصتي؟
- That's right. - No one wants to hear my story.
- هذا صحيح. - لا أحد يريد أن يسمع قصتي.
- What's your reason? - We visited your place.
- ما هو السبب الخاص بك؟ - زرنا مكانك.
My place?
مكاني؟
Yes, it was very clean.
نعم، لقد كانت نظيفة جداً.
Everything was neatly organized,
كل شيء كان منظماً بدقة،
even your socks.
حتى الجوارب الخاصة بك.
I don't like it when things are messy.
أنا لا أحب ذلك عندما تكون الأمور فوضوية.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
So you must be having a hard time here.
لذلك يجب أن تواجه وقتًا عصيبًا هنا.
Right?
يمين؟
Every day, you have to eat and sleep...
كل يوم عليك أن تأكل وتنام..
right next to strangers who committed all sorts of crimes.
بجوار الغرباء الذين ارتكبوا جميع أنواع الجرائم.
It must be awful.
يجب أن يكون فظيعا.
It is awful.
إنه أمر مروع.
So...
لذا...
why don't you...
لماذا لا...
tell us more about yourself?
أخبرنا المزيد عن نفسك؟
The people here...
الناس هنا...
probably think that you're like them and treat you as one of them.
ربما تعتقد أنك مثلهم ويعاملونك كواحد منهم.
But in our eyes,
ولكن في أعيننا
you seem a little different.
يبدو أنك مختلف قليلا.
Well...
حسنا...
They don't even wash themselves often.
حتى أنهم لا يغسلون أنفسهم كثيرًا.
They stink, and the cell is small and filthy.
كانت رائحتها كريهة، والزنزانة صغيرة وقذرة.
It's really driving me crazy.
إنه يقودني إلى الجنون حقًا.
Right, I'm sure.
صحيح، أنا متأكد.
So this was what we were wondering.
لذلك كان هذا ما كنا نتساءل عنه.
Perhaps you...
ربما أنت...
didn't actually intend to kill Soo Hyun...
لم يكن ينوي في الواقع قتل سو هيون…
That's right, I...
هذا صحيح، أنا...
I never intended to kill her.
لم أقصد قتلها أبداً
That is why we want to hear your story.
ولهذا السبب نريد أن نسمع قصتك.
To find out exactly how different you are from the others.
لمعرفة مدى اختلافك عن الآخرين.
You look like you've lost quite a bit of weight.
يبدو أنك فقدت قدرًا كبيرًا من الوزن.
Have you been eating well?
هل كنت تأكل جيدا؟
Then why don't we...
ثم لماذا لا...
eat something first before we start talking?
أكل شيئا أولا قبل أن نبدأ الحديث؟
How are you feeling?
كيف تشعر؟
I got to have a proper meal for a change.
يجب أن أتناول وجبة مناسبة من أجل التغيير.
I wish every day was like today.
أتمنى أن يكون كل يوم مثل اليوم.
Do you regret it?
هل تندم على ذلك؟
She was in the wrong place at the wrong time.
لقد كانت في المكان الخطأ في الوقت الخطأ.
Are you talking about Soo Hyun? What exactly do you mean by that?
هل تتحدثين عن سو هيون؟ ماذا تقصد بالضبط بذلك؟
Blame her bad luck.
إلقاء اللوم على سوء حظها.
It's Soo Hyun.
إنها سو هيون.
Her name.
اسمها.
Lee Soo Hyun.
لي سو هيون.
Had she not come to that place that day,
لو أنها لم تأتي إلى ذلك المكان في ذلك اليوم،
nothing would have happened to her or me.
لن يحدث شيء لها أو لي.
Do you think...
هل تعتقد...
it's Soo Hyun's fault that you ended up like this?
هل هو خطأ سو هيون أن انتهى بك الأمر هكذا؟
It is her fault for catching my attention.
إنه خطأها لجذب انتباهي.
I wonder what was on his mind...
وأتساءل ماذا كان يدور في ذهنه..
as Cho Hyun Gil was watching such an innocent child.
كما كان تشو هيون جيل يراقب مثل هذا الطفل البريء.
Why does he feel differently from the rest of us?
لماذا يشعر بشكل مختلف عن بقيتنا؟
Are you from Samcheonpo?
هل أنت من سامشونبو؟
I don't hear an accent though.
أنا لا أسمع لهجة رغم ذلك.
I moved to Seoul when I was 15.
انتقلت إلى سيول عندما كان عمري 15 عامًا.
In eighth grade?
في الصف الثامن؟
I didn't go to middle school.
لم أذهب إلى المدرسة المتوسطة.
I started working as soon as I graduated from elementary school.
بدأت العمل فور تخرجي من المدرسة الابتدائية.
What kind of work?
أي نوع من العمل؟
I worked at factories,
عملت في المصانع
sold fish, and worked at butcher shops.
باع السمك وعمل في محلات الجزارة.
I did everything I was told to do.
لقد فعلت كل ما قيل لي أن أفعله.
I had to work all sorts of jobs too.
كان علي أن أعمل في جميع أنواع الوظائف أيضًا.
My family was very poor when I was young.
كانت عائلتي فقيرة جدًا عندما كنت صغيرًا.
Since I'm the eldest son,
وبما أنني الابن الأكبر،
I had to help my parents on their farm...
كان علي أن أساعد والدي في مزرعتهم...
and sell our harvest.
ونبيع محصولنا.
I did all sorts of things.
فعلت كل أنواع الأشياء.
Detective, what did you say your name was?
Detective, what did you say your name was?
My name?
اسمي؟
I'm Kook Young Soo.
أنا كوك يونغ سو.
Detective Kook, then did you also quit school after elementary school?
أيها المحقق كوك، هل تركت المدرسة أيضًا بعد المدرسة الابتدائية؟
I entered middle school a year later than everyone else.
دخلت المدرسة المتوسطة بعد عام من أي شخص آخر.
I see. At least you went to middle school.
أرى. At least you went to middle school.
- You think you two are different? - What do you mean?
- You think you two are different? - ماذا تقصد؟
You were both poor, and both of you struggled.
You were both poor, and both of you struggled.
But he attended middle school, so his situation was different.
لكنه التحق بالمدرسة المتوسطة، فكان وضعه مختلفًا.
My life could've turned out differently too.
My life could've turned out differently too.
Do you think that's why you ended up becoming a criminal?
هل تعتقد أن هذا هو السبب الذي جعلك تصبح مجرمًا؟
Because you had to quit school?
Because you had to quit school?
Well...
حسنا...
I...
أنا...
- Detective. - Yes.
- المخبر. - نعم.
Can you get me a soda?
هل يمكنك أن تحضر لي صودا؟
I have a habit of drinking one after every meal.
I have a habit of drinking one after every meal.
(Please keep this cubicle clean.)
(Please keep this cubicle clean.)
(If you have a dream, you can start afresh.)
(If you have a dream, you can start afresh.)
(Korea Correctional Service)
(Korea Correctional Service)
She was in the wrong place at the wrong time.
She was in the wrong place at the wrong time.
Blame her bad luck.
إلقاء اللوم على سوء حظها.
Hey.
يا.
- Are you all right? - Of course.
- هل أنت بخير؟ - بالطبع.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
You quit smoking.
لقد أقلعت عن التدخين.
Yes, what's up?
نعم، ما الأمر؟
Why do you carry a lighter around?
Why do you carry a lighter around?
Oh, this thing?
أوه، هذا الشيء؟
For emergencies.
لحالات الطوارئ.
I'm sure there will come a day when I'll crave a smoke.
أنا متأكد أنه سيأتي يوم سأشتهي فيه الدخان.
If I don't have a lighter at that time,
If I don't have a lighter at that time,
I may seriously go crazy.
I may seriously go crazy.
(Through the Darkness, Episode 5)
(Through the Darkness, Episode 5)
(Proposal: 1 Year Plan of Behavioral Analysis Team)
(المقترح: خطة لمدة عام لفريق التحليل السلوكي)
We just got started,
لقد بدأنا للتو،
so let us do this for just one more year.
so let us do this for just one more year.
Yes, there's our proposal.
Yes, there's our proposal.
We'll work quietly so that you'll never notice us.
سنعمل بهدوء حتى لا تلاحظنا أبدًا.
Right here. Please.
هنا. لو سمحت.
So please... Help me out.
So please... Help me out.
Sit down.
اجلس.
- My gosh. - Just one more year.
- يا إلهي. - سنة أخرى فقط.
This year's college entrance exam must have been rather easy.
لا بد أن امتحان القبول بالجامعة هذا العام كان سهلاً إلى حد ما.
- Arms down. - The cut-off scores...
- الأسلحة إلى أسفل. - الدرجات المقطوعة...
for many universities went up by even ten points.
بالنسبة للعديد من الجامعات ارتفعت حتى عشر نقاط.
- Reported by Lee Yong Nam. - All done.
- Reported by Lee Yong Nam. - تم كل شيء.
The college exam score cut-off for this year's acceptance...
تحديد نتيجة امتحان الكلية للقبول لهذا العام...
for Seoul National University's Humanities Department had been...
لقسم العلوم الإنسانية بجامعة سيول الوطنية...
- Salute! - We'll do our best!
- تحية! - سنبذل قصارى جهدنا!
(January 2001)
(يناير 2001)
(March 2001)
(مارس 2001)
(We will care for your family with love and sincerity.)
(سوف نعتني بعائلتك بالحب والإخلاص.)
(True Correction, Bright Future, For a future with hope)
(التصحيح الحقيقي، مستقبل مشرق، لمستقبل مليء بالأمل)
(May 2001)
(مايو 2001)
A terrorist attack on the US...
A terrorist attack on the US...
put Americans and people around the world in great shock.
وضع الأميركيين والناس في جميع أنحاء العالم في صدمة كبيرة.
(September 2001)
(سبتمبر 2001)
One second.
ثانية واحدة.
(October 2001)
(أكتوبر 2001)
(November 2001)
(نوفمبر 2001)
(December 2001)
(ديسمبر 2001)
- Excuse me. - One second.
- عفوا. - ثانية واحدة.
(Do not scrub in the bath)
(Do not scrub in the bath)
(December 2001)
(ديسمبر 2001)
(January 2002)
(يناير 2002)
- Yes. - If you give us one more chance,
- نعم. - If you give us one more chance,
we will repay your kindness with great performance.
سوف نرد لطفك بأداء رائع.
Yes, sir.
نعم يا سيدي.
(Extended by 1 year)
(تمديد لمدة سنة واحدة)
Thank you!
شكرا لك!
Today is a historical day.
Today is a historical day.
Our dream of reaching the semifinals of the World Cup came true.
لقد تحقق حلمنا بالوصول إلى الدور نصف النهائي من كأس العالم.
I still have a tough time believing it.
I still have a tough time believing it.
- Go, Korea! Hey! - Go, Korea!
- اذهبي كوريا! يا! - اذهبي كوريا!
All right!
حسنًا!
- Go, Korea! - Go, Korea!
- اذهبي كوريا! - اذهبي كوريا!
(November 2002)
(نوفمبر 2002)
Good grief!
حزن جيد!
Hey, let him go. Guard!
مهلا، دعه يذهب. يحمي!
You can take him away.
يمكنك أن تأخذه بعيدا.
Darn it.
الرتق.
(December 2002)
(ديسمبر 2002)
I'm aware.
أنا على علم.
So why did you go that far and commit that crime?
فلماذا ذهبت إلى هذا الحد وارتكبت تلك الجريمة؟
My gosh, these detectives.
My gosh, these detectives.
(New hope! 2003)
(أمل جديد! 2003)
Although the temperature is well below zero,
Although the temperature is well below zero,
the beach is filled with people...
the beach is filled with people...
waiting for the first sunrise.
في انتظار شروق الشمس الأول.
I got some buns.
حصلت على بعض الكعك.
- The number of people... - Look at this.
- عدد الأشخاص... - انظر إلى هذا.
My gosh.
يا إلهي.
(February 2003)
(فبراير 2003)
(March 2003)
(مارس 2003)
(April 2003)
(أبريل 2003)
(July 2003)
(يوليو 2003)
(August 2003)
(أغسطس 2003)
(Korean Beef Gopchang)
(لحم بقري جوبتشانج الكوري)
How long has it been since we had a team dinner?
كم من الوقت مضى منذ أن تناولنا عشاء الفريق؟
Eat up while you can.
تناول الطعام بينما تستطيع.
You may never see another day like this.
قد لا ترى يومًا آخر مثل هذا أبدًا.
You can eat. I'll grill these.
يمكنك أن تأكل. سوف أقوم بشوي هذه.
It's all right. I'm an expert at grilling,
كل شيء على ما يرام. انا خبير في الشواء
so I never let anyone else do it.
لذلك أنا لا أسمح لأي شخص آخر أن يفعل ذلك.
Well, I'll show you what I can do. Give it here.
حسنًا، سأريكم ما يمكنني فعله. اعطها هنا.
No, sir.
لا يا سيدي.
Please just eat this. It's hot.
من فضلك فقط أكل هذا. الطقس حار.
It's good.
انها جيدة.
Please evaluate my skills.
يرجى تقييم مهاراتي.
- I'll eat it myself. - My gosh.
- سأكلها بنفسي. - يا إلهي.
- You should eat too. - Okay.
- يجب أن تأكل أيضا. - تمام.
All right, then. Let's continue to hang in there.
حسنًا إذن. دعونا نستمر في التعلق هناك.
Okay.
تمام.
- Great work. - Bottoms up.
- عمل عظيم. - قيعان تصل.
Weather newsflash.
أخبار الطقس العاجلة.
The typhoon is heading north,
الإعصار يتجه نحو الشمال
making many parents worried as they wait for their children.
مما يثير قلق العديد من الآباء أثناء انتظار أطفالهم.
Typhoon 14, also known as Maemi,
إعصار 14، المعروف أيضًا باسم مايمي،
will cause strong winds to blow...
will cause strong winds to blow...
as well as heavy rain throughout the entire country.
فضلا عن الأمطار الغزيرة في جميع أنحاء البلاد.
The wind speed of Maemi can reach up to 60m per second.
يمكن أن تصل سرعة الرياح في مايمي إلى 60 مترًا في الثانية.
It first headed to Taiwan,
It first headed to Taiwan,
then suddenly changed course...
then suddenly changed course...
and began to head to the Korean peninsula.
and began to head to the Korean peninsula.
Honey, I'm home.
عزيزتي، أنا في المنزل.
Wait, honey...
انتظري يا عزيزتي...
No.
لا.
Honey!
عزيزي!
What's...
ما...
- There was another one. - No, why...
- كان هناك واحد آخر. - لا لماذا...
(I wanted to take this woman, so I shut her mouth and took her.)
(أردت أن آخذ هذه المرأة، فأغلقت فمها وأخذتها).
(She was already dead before I could do anything. I got angry.)
(لقد كانت ميتة بالفعل قبل أن أتمكن من فعل أي شيء. لقد غضبت).
(Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency)
(وكالة شرطة العاصمة سيول)
So do you know who the new chief is?
So do you know who the new chief is?
Sorry?
آسف؟
Oh, right.
أوه، صحيح.
What's wrong? What's with that face?
ما هو الخطأ؟ ما بال هذا الوجه؟
Oh, you're here.
أوه، أنت هنا.
Hey, good morning, Tae Gu.
Hey, good morning, Tae Gu.
Have you been well?
هل كنت بخير؟
Why didn't you tell me?
لماذا لم تخبرني؟
You could've at least given me a heads up.
You could've at least given me a heads up.
Everyone already knew.
الجميع يعرف بالفعل.
I didn't need to do that.
I didn't need to do that.
Everyone except me, who has to take orders from him.
الجميع باستثناءي، الذي عليه أن يتلقى الأوامر منه.
I mean, I thought...
يعني اعتقدت...
you already knew too, Captain Yoon.
you already knew too, Captain Yoon.
I understand.
أفهم.
Goodness, hello.
الخير، مرحبا.
I'm Kim Bong Sik, the new chief of the Special Crime Squad.
أنا كيم بونج سيك، الرئيس الجديد لفرقة الجرائم الخاصة.
- Hello. - Nice to meet you.
- مرحبًا. - سعيد بلقائك.
I hope we all get along.
آمل أن نتفق جميعا.
- Yes. - It's nice to meet you.
- نعم. - تشرفنا.
Let's grab some soju sometime.
Let's grab some soju sometime.
- Sure. - Okay.
- بالتأكيد. - تمام.
If you knew Kim Bong Sik was coming as our new chief,
إذا كنت تعلم أن كيم بونج سيك سيأتي كرئيسنا الجديد،
you of all people could've let me know.
you of all people could've let me know.
I thought you'd only get stressed if I told you ahead of time.
اعتقدت أنك ستتوتر فقط إذا أخبرتك مسبقًا.
Also, nothing would change anyway.
Also, nothing would change anyway.
Nothing could be changed,
Nothing could be changed,
so I happened to be the only one who didn't know?
لذلك كنت الوحيد الذي لا يعرف؟
No, that's not what I meant.
لا، هذا ليس ما قصدته.
Well...
حسنا...
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
There's no need for you to apologize.
There's no need for you to apologize.
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
It probably wasn't easy for you either.
It probably wasn't easy for you either.
- Does the Analysis Team know? - The Analysis Team?
- Does the Analysis Team know? - فريق التحليل؟
Back when they were at Jungbu Station,
Back when they were at Jungbu Station,
I heard Song Ha Young...
سمعت سونغ ها يونغ...
once betrayed Chief Kim Bong Sik.
once betrayed Chief Kim Bong Sik.
People in this field really love rumors,
People in this field really love rumors,
don't they?
أليس كذلك؟
(Hwang Dae Sun, rape and mutilation murderer)
(Hwang Dae Sun, rape and mutilation murderer)
Why are you back?
لماذا عدت؟
We still do not understand why you committed these crimes, Mr. Hwang.
ما زلنا لا نفهم سبب ارتكابك لهذه الجرائم يا سيد هوانج.
(Keep quiet)
(التزم الصمت)
So we came...
لذلك جئنا...
to hear the story of your life, Mr. Hwang.
to hear the story of your life, Mr. Hwang.
What story?
اي قصة؟
Well, can you share the stories of your childhood?
حسنًا، هل يمكنك مشاركة قصص طفولتك؟
What will you do with the stories of my unfortunate childhood?
ماذا ستفعل بقصص طفولتي المؤسفة؟
I guess you had lots of bad memories.
I guess you had lots of bad memories.
In that case,
في تلك الحالة،
can you tell me one thing that made you the angriest?
هل يمكنك أن تخبرني بشيء واحد جعلك الأكثر غضبًا؟
It's my dad.
إنه والدي.
He always beat me up without a reason.
He always beat me up without a reason.
He'd beat me up during meals,
He'd beat me up during meals,
and beat me for going to school.
and beat me for going to school.
There were days when I actually skipped school...
كانت هناك أيام عندما تغيبت عن المدرسة بالفعل.
because he hurt me so badly.
because he hurt me so badly.
Whenever he beat me, he stripped me down to my underwear,
كلما كان يضربني، كان يجردني من ملابسي الداخلية،
then kicked me out of the house.
then kicked me out of the house.
So I sat in front of the gate.
So I sat in front of the gate.
So if your neighborhood friends saw you,
So if your neighborhood friends saw you,
they would've teased you a lot.
they would've teased you a lot.
Kids would make fun of me until I went to middle school.
كان الأطفال يسخرون مني حتى ذهبت إلى المدرسة المتوسطة.
I'd beat them up too.
كنت سأضربهم أيضًا.
I never hung out with them.
I never hung out with them.
Those emotions must have been tough on you.
Those emotions must have been tough on you.
And it must've been embarrassing that you weren't wearing clothes.
ولابد أنه كان محرجًا أنك لم تكن ترتدي ملابس.
How did you usually deal with your anger?
How did you usually deal with your anger?
There wasn't much I could do as a kid.
There wasn't much I could do as a kid.
All I could do was kill animals because they couldn't talk.
كل ما أمكنني فعله هو قتل الحيوانات لأنها لا تستطيع التحدث.
I killed my next-door neighbor's cow with a sickle.
لقد قتلت بقرة جارتي بالمنجل.
I caught a dog in my neighborhood...
I caught a dog in my neighborhood...
and watched it jump and bark in the hot, boiling water.
وشاهدته وهو يقفز وينبح في الماء الساخن المغلي.
Watching that got me off.
مشاهدة هذا أخرجني.
My father stripped me and kicked me out countless times.
لقد جردني والدي من ملابسي وطردني مرات لا تحصى.
So I still hate it when my body is exposed.
لذلك ما زلت أكره عندما يتعرض جسدي.
It infuriates me.
إنه يغضبني.
No matter how hot it is, I never wear shorts or short sleeves.
مهما كان الجو حارا، لا أرتدي أبدا السراويل القصيرة أو الأكمام القصيرة.
After you killed animals,
بعد أن قتلت الحيوانات
did you dismember them too?
هل قمت بتقطيعهم أيضا؟
Sometimes.
أحيانا.
I tried cutting them up.
حاولت تقطيعهم.
I learned cooking at a restaurant.
تعلمت الطبخ في أحد المطاعم.
Using a knife to cut them into pieces was fun.
كان استخدام السكين لتقطيعها إلى قطع أمرًا ممتعًا.
Your second female victim.
ضحيتك الأنثوية الثانية.
Is that why you cut off the flesh on her leg...
ألهذا السبب قطعت لحم ساقها...
after you raped and murdered her?
بعد أن اغتصبتها وقتلتها؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
I wanted to cut it off when she was alive.
أردت أن أقطعها عندما كانت على قيد الحياة.
But she kept moving, and her blood splattered.
لكنها ظلت تتحرك، وتناثر دمها.
So I stopped for a bit.
لذلك توقفت قليلا.
After I killed her,
بعد أن قتلتها
I sat next to her and tried to cut it off again.
جلست بجانبها وحاولت قطعها مرة أخرى.
But I don't remember much because I was drunk.
لكنني لا أتذكر الكثير لأنني كنت في حالة سكر.
Then you took it home.
ثم أخذته إلى المنزل.
But no one saw you?
لكن لم يراك أحد؟
It was dripping in blood.
كان يقطر في الدم.
I bet it must've scared people.
أراهن أنه لا بد أنه أخاف الناس.
Why? They wouldn't know what it was.
لماذا؟ لن يعرفوا ما هو.
I thought it was meat for a second...
اعتقدت أنه كان لحمًا للحظة.
when I woke up the next day.
عندما استيقظت في اليوم التالي.
Which one is it? You don't remember? Or you don't want to talk to us?
أي واحد هو؟ أنت لا تتذكر؟ أم أنك لا تريد التحدث معنا؟
It's both.
إنه كلاهما.
Must I tell you everything?
Must I tell you everything?
You said it wasn't an interrogation.
You said it wasn't an interrogation.
(Implement an improved reform system for the future)
(تنفيذ نظام إصلاحي محسن للمستقبل)
- Good day. - Good day.
- يوم جيد. - يوم جيد.
Hwang Dae Sun definitely shows the behaviors of serial killers.
يُظهر هوانج داي صن بالتأكيد سلوكيات القتلة المتسلسلين.
Right. But why do you think he cut off the flesh on her leg?
يمين. لكن لماذا تعتقد أنه قطع لحم ساقها؟
It looks like he didn't know either.
It looks like he didn't know either.
I think his rage against his abusive father...
I think his rage against his abusive father...
developed into abnormal sexual behaviors.
developed into abnormal sexual behaviors.
Then his rage caused him to mutilate the body too.
ثم دفعه غضبه إلى تشويه الجسد أيضًا.
Right.
يمين.
Gosh.
يا إلهي.
Many organizations are trying to support flood victims...
تحاول العديد من المنظمات دعم ضحايا الفيضانات ...
from Typhoon Maemi which struck the Korean Peninsula pretty hard.
من إعصار مايمي الذي ضرب شبه الجزيرة الكورية بشدة.
The civic organizations...
The civic organizations...
How may I help you?
كيف يمكنني مساعدتك؟
(No smoking)
(ممنوع التدخين)
Is this the Behavioral Analysis Team?
Is this the Behavioral Analysis Team?
- Yes. - Where's Song Ha Young?
- نعم. - أين سونغ ها يونغ؟
Inspector Song? He's out for an interview.
أغنية المفتش؟ He's out for an interview.
"Inspector"?
"مفتش"؟
Should I tell him you stopped by when he comes back?
هل يجب أن أخبره أنك توقفت عندما يعود؟
("Sky, Wind, Star, and Poetry" by Yun Dong Ju)
("Sky, Wind, Star, and Poetry" by Yun Dong Ju)
He hasn't changed.
لم يتغير.
What brings you here?
ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا؟
Don't mind me.
لا مانع لي.
Get back to work.
العودة إلى العمل.
It's like nothing ever happened. This isn't fair.
It's like nothing ever happened. هذا ليس عادلا.
What?
ماذا؟
The weather.
الطقس.
The weather can't be this good. It's cheating.
لا يمكن أن يكون الطقس جيدًا إلى هذا الحد. إنه الغش.
The pain and sense of loss.
الألم والشعور بالخسارة.
The suffering...
المعاناة...
is only up to the victims to bear.
الأمر متروك فقط للضحايا لتحمله.
I bet some people are enjoying this good weather.
أراهن أن بعض الناس يستمتعون بهذا الطقس الجيد.
All right.
حسنًا.
He's not even investigating the case. Why is he reading...
إنه حتى لا يحقق في القضية. لماذا يقرأ...؟
the case reports for the detectives?
تقارير الحالة للمباحث؟
Seriously. This nosy jerk.
بجد. هذا النطر الفضولي.
Hey. When he comes back, I'll tell him you were...
يا. وعندما يعود سأخبره أنك كنت...
You!
أنت!
"Hey"?
"يا"؟
Read what it says on my name card.
اقرأ ما هو مكتوب على بطاقة اسمي.
"Special Crime Squad Chief, Kim Bong Sik."
"رئيس فرقة الجرائم الخاصة، كيم بونج سيك".
Are you blind?
هل أنت أعمى؟
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
You seem to have picked up bad habits from Song Ha Young.
يبدو أنك قد تعلمت عادات سيئة من Song Ha Young.
You're still wet behind your ears.
أنت لا تزال مبللا خلف أذنيك.
No, I just mean this is the office for the Behavioral Analysis Team.
لا، أعني فقط أن هذا هو مكتب فريق التحليل السلوكي.
You need to tell me why you are here.
عليك أن تخبرني لماذا أنت هنا.
You are going to make me repeat myself.
أنت سوف تجعلني أكرر نفسي.
You just mind your own business!
أنت فقط تهتم بشؤونك الخاصة!
I'm back.
لقد عدت.
Have you been well, Assistant Inspector Song?
هل كنت بخير، مساعد المفتش سونغ؟
Right. I heard you're an inspector now. Inspector Song.
يمين. سمعت أنك مفتش الآن. أغنية المفتش.
Goodness. You seem well.
الخير. تبدو بخير.
What do you guys do here? Why are you dressed up?
ماذا تفعلون هنا يا رفاق؟ لماذا ترتدي ملابسك؟
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
I don't expect you to give me a warm welcome.
لا أتوقع منك أن ترحب بي ترحيبا حارا.
But it's only polite to say hello when you see your superior.
ولكن من الأدب أن تقول مرحبًا عندما ترى رئيسك.
Don't you agree?
ألا توافق؟
Seriously. This team is full of rude punks.
بجد. هذا الفريق مليء بالأشرار الوقحين.
Hello. I'm Statistics Analyst Jung Woo Ju.
مرحبًا. أنا محلل الإحصاء جونغ وو جو.
Statistics analyst?
محلل احصائي؟
You guys have difficult titles here.
يا رفاق لديكم ألقاب صعبة هنا.
Dumb people won't be able to remember them.
لن يتمكن الأغبياء من تذكرهم.
What was it called?
ماذا كان يسمى؟
Right. A profiler.
يمين. ملف التعريف.
If you need to talk to me, let's talk outside.
إذا كنت بحاجة إلى التحدث معي، دعونا نتحدث في الخارج.
I have nothing to say to you in private.
ليس لدي ما أقوله لك على انفراد.
I just wanted to say hello since I was in the building.
أردت فقط أن أقول مرحباً منذ أن كنت في المبنى.
And I wanted to check out what you do here.
وأردت التحقق مما تفعله هنا.
Why is the door open? Did...
لماذا الباب مفتوح؟ هل...
It's been a while, Captain Kook.
لقد مر وقت طويل يا كابتن كوك.
I've been transferred to the Special Crime Squad today.
لقد تم نقلي إلى فرقة الجرائم الخاصة اليوم.
We'll be running into each other a lot.
سنواجه بعضنا البعض كثيرًا.
I look forward to working with you.
وإنني أتطلع إلى العمل معك.
- Okay. - It was nice to see everyone.
- تمام. - كان من الجميل أن أرى الجميع.
Right. I bought this for you.
يمين. اشتريت هذا لك.
I almost forgot.
لقد نسيت تقريبا.
You still eat chocolates like a little kid, right?
مازلت تأكل الشوكولاتة مثل طفل صغير، أليس كذلك؟
We'll be seeing each other every day even if you don't want to.
سنرى بعضنا البعض كل يوم حتى لو كنت لا ترغب في ذلك.
Let's put our past behind us.
دعونا نضع ماضينا وراءنا.
See you around.
أراك بالجوار.
All right.
حسنًا.
Who was that?
من كان ذلك؟
Just as I heard, he's one rude cop.
كما سمعت، فهو شرطي فظ.
I was wondering how great his career was going...
كنت أتساءل عن مدى روعة مسيرته المهنية..
after he stabbed me, his mentor, in the back.
بعد أن طعنني، معلمه، في الظهر.
You've got to be kidding me. An inspector?
لا بد أنك تمزح معي. مفتش؟
(November 1996)
(نوفمبر 1996)
Search every nook and cranny of the neighborhood.
ابحث في كل زاوية وركن في الحي.
He's wearing a black jacket with a hoodie and black sneakers.
إنه يرتدي سترة سوداء مع هوديي وحذاء رياضي أسود.
Find him now!
ابحث عنه الآن!
I'm chasing a man who fits the description.
أنا أطارد رجلاً يناسب الوصف.
I'm sorry. I lost him.
أنا آسف. لقد فقدته.
Yoon Tae Gu, where are you?
يون تاي جو، أين أنت؟
Where are you?
أين أنت؟
Let go of me.
اتركني.
Gosh.
يا إلهي.
Darn it.
الرتق.
Jung Soo Chan.
جونغ سو تشان.
You're under arrest...
أنت رهن الاعتقال..
for robbery, murder, and fleeing.
بتهم السرقة والقتل والهروب.
You have the right to consult an attorney...
من حقك الاستعانة بمحامي..
- and to remain silent. - Get him!
- وأن يبقى صامتا. - احصل عليه!
Gosh.
يا إلهي.
Did you catch him?
هل قبضت عليه؟
Gosh. You really are a detective now.
يا إلهي. أنت حقا محقق الآن.
Hey. We got him.
يا. لقد حصلنا عليه.
Don't stand there. Get him.
لا تقف هناك. احصل عليه.
Yoon Tae Gu caught Jung Soo Chan.
أمسك يون تاي غو بجونغ سو تشان.
Nice, Detective Yoon.
رائع، أيها المحقق يون.
She got him.
لقد حصلت عليه.
This punk.
هذا فاسق.
You set an example for your fellow officers...
لقد كنت قدوة لزملائك الضباط..
by promptly arresting a robbery and murder suspect...
القبض على متهم بالسرقة والقتل على الفور..
who was on the run after committing a brutal crime.
الذي كان هارباً بعد ارتكابه جريمة وحشية.
Hence, I hereby award...
ومن هنا فإنني أمنح...
Inspector Yoon Tae Gu.
المفتش يون تاي جو.
(Special Promotion Ceremony)
(حفل الترويج الخاص)
Yoon Tae Gu!
يون تاي جو!
- Come on. Let's shout together. - Tae Gu, you rock.
- تعال. دعونا نصرخ معا. - تاي قو، أنت صخرة.
- Well done! - Go, Yoon Tae Gu!
- أحسنت! - اذهب، يون تاي قو!
Oh, my. You really look like a cop now.
يا بلدي. أنت تبدو حقا مثل شرطي الآن.
Who knew you'd last this long? I thought you'd quit to get married.
من كان يعلم أنك ستصمدين كل هذه المدة؟ اعتقدت أنك سوف تستقيل لتتزوج.
- Come on. - She's so cool.
- تعال. - إنها رائعة جدًا.
At this rate, you'll be promoted to commissioner in no time.
بهذا المعدل، سيتم ترقيتك إلى مفوض في أي وقت من الأوقات.
- For sure. - Tae Gu can definitely do that.
- بالتأكيد. - يمكن لـ Tae Gu فعل ذلك بالتأكيد.
Could you take a photo of us?
هل يمكنك التقاط صورة لنا؟
- Sure! - Can we join?
- بالتأكيد! - هل يمكننا الانضمام؟
You even got a special promotion thanks to Song Ha Young.
لقد حصلت أيضًا على ترقية خاصة بفضل Song Ha Young.
I'm surprised you're holding out so well, Yoon Tae Gu.
أنا مندهش أنك صامد بشكل جيد، يون تاي جو.
Okay, let's try that one more time.
حسنا، دعونا نحاول ذلك مرة أخرى.
Nice, that looks great. Make a V.
جميل، هذا يبدو رائعا. اصنع V.
Captain.
كابتن.
- Captain Yoon. - Yes.
- الكابتن يون. - نعم.
Superintendent Baek wants to meet with you.
المشرف بايك يريد مقابلتك.
Superintendent Baek? Why?
المشرف بايك؟ لماذا؟
I have no idea.
ليس لدي أي فكرة.
He asked for Chief Kim Bong Sik too,
لقد سأل عن الزعيم كيم بونج سيك أيضًا،
but I don't know where he is now.
لكني لا أعرف أين هو الآن.
Cheers.
هتافات.
It's nice to have you back.
من الجميل أن نعود إليك.
You're the only one who's happy to see me,
أنت الوحيد الذي سعيد برؤيتي
so I'm not sure whether or not I've been doing well so far.
لذلك لست متأكدًا مما إذا كنت في حالة جيدة حتى الآن أم لا.
Come on. I really meant it. Must you twist my words like this?
تعال. أنا حقا يعني ذلك. هل يجب عليك تحريف كلامي مثل هذا؟
What you need is my intel, not me.
ما تحتاجه هو معلوماتي، وليس أنا.
That's what makes you indispensable.
وهذا ما يجعلك لا غنى عنه.
Anyway, pretend not to know me when you see me at HQ.
على أية حال، تظاهر بأنك لا تعرفني عندما تراني في المقر الرئيسي.
Goodness. Don't you worry.
الخير. لا تقلق.
Life is full of ironies.
الحياة مليئة بالمفارقات.
Song Ha Young and even Yoon Tae Gu.
سونغ ها يونغ وحتى يون تاي غو.
Who knew I'd meet them again here?
من كان يعلم أنني سأقابلهم مرة أخرى هنا؟
Is this fate or something?
هل هذا هو المصير أم ماذا؟
Did you meet Inspector Song Ha Young?
هل قابلت المفتش سونغ ها يونغ؟
Yes, I sure did.
نعم بالتأكيد فعلت.
I can't figure out what his team does.
لا أستطيع معرفة ما يفعله فريقه.
When you stab someone in the back, it all comes back to you...
عندما تطعن شخص ما في ظهره، فكل شيء يعود إليك..
Darn it. There's one exception.
الرتق. هناك استثناء واحد.
Who? You?
من؟ أنت؟
You little...
أنت قليلا...
Remember? The head prosecutor...
تذكر؟ رئيس النيابة...
who asked for Yoon Tae Gu back then.
الذي طلب يون تاي غو في ذلك الوقت.
(Head Prosecutor Lee Dong Ju)
(المدعي العام لي دونغ جو)
Here.
هنا.
It's classified information, so don't reveal your source.
إنها معلومات سرية، لذا لا تكشف عن مصدرك.
Investigate it alone, quietly.
التحقيق في الأمر وحده، بهدوء.
This is credible info, right?
هذه معلومات موثوقة، أليس كذلك؟
Have I ever lied to you?
هل كذبت عليك من قبل؟
Go through it. There's solid evidence too.
اذهب من خلال ذلك. هناك أدلة قوية أيضا.
Why did I miss all this?
لماذا فاتني كل هذا؟
Yoon Tae Gu is one of your direct reports, right?
يون تاي جو هو أحد مرؤوسيك المباشرين، أليس كذلك؟
Yes, sir.
نعم يا سيدي.
- Hello. - Where is Room Ten?
- مرحبًا. - أين الغرفة العاشرة؟
It's this way. You'll find it on your left.
إنها بهذه الطريقة. ستجده على يسارك.
Yoon Tae Gu.
يون تاي جو.
I mean, Detective Yoon.
أعني، المحقق يون.
We're now getting the hang of working together as a team,
لقد بدأنا الآن في العمل معًا كفريق واحد،
and you worked hard on this case,
ولقد عملت بجد في هذه القضية،
so I want to buy you a drink.
لذلك أريد أن أشتري لك مشروبا.
Hurry up and meet me here, okay?
أسرع وقابلني هنا، حسنًا؟
- I'm telling you. - My goodness.
- أنا أقول لك. - يا إلهي.
Oh, there she is. Come on in.
أوه، ها هي. ادخل.
You made it. Take a seat.
لقد نجحت. شغل مقعدا.
Come on. Take a seat.
تعال. شغل مقعدا.
Come on!
تعال!
Hey, where are you going?
مهلا، إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
Are you a bar girl or what?
هل أنت فتاة بار أم ماذا؟
Goodness, it's such a hot mess.
يا إلهي، إنها فوضى عارمة.
How dare you disgrace the entire police force?
كيف تجرؤ على إهانة قوة الشرطة بأكملها؟
- Detective Yoon, this is nuts. - How embarrassing.
- المحقق يون، هذا جنون. - كم هو محرج.
Remember? The head prosecutor...
يتذكر؟ رئيس النيابة...
who asked for Yoon Tae Gu back then.
الذي طلب يون تاي غو في ذلك الوقت.
I ended up taking bribes...
وانتهى بي الأمر بأخذ رشاوى..
from a building contractor against my will...
من مقاول بناء رغما عني...
and arrested a fake suspect.
والقبض على مشتبه به مزيف.
Because of that, I was branded a corrupt cop.
ولهذا السبب، وُصفت بالشرطي الفاسد.
Everything was set up so he'd look like the real culprit.
تم إعداد كل شيء حتى يبدو وكأنه الجاني الحقيقي.
Anyone would have believed it.
كان يمكن لأي شخص أن يصدق ذلك.
Song Ha Young didn't buy it!
سونغ ها يونغ لم تشتريه!
That punk really gets on my nerves.
هذا الشرير يثير أعصابي حقًا.
He has to get in the way of everything I do.
عليه أن يعيق كل ما أفعله.
I got demoted because of that jerk.
لقد تم تخفيض رتبتي بسبب ذلك الأحمق.
But you're back now.
لكنك عدت الآن.
Song Ha Young was branded...
تم تصنيف سونغ ها يونغ...
a backstabbing troublemaker...
مشاغب طعن في الظهر...
who betrays his superiors.
الذي يخون رؤسائه.
That's why he's working in that dump of an office now.
لهذا السبب فهو يعمل في مكب النفايات هذا بالمكتب الآن.
That's not enough.
هذا لا يكفي.
He acts like a gentleman to your face...
يتصرف كرجل نبيل في وجهك..
but skims the cream off the top behind your back.
لكن يزيل الكريم من الأعلى خلف ظهرك.
Everyone needs to know that.
الجميع بحاجة إلى معرفة ذلك.
Bong Sik.
بونج سيك.
I'll only trust Chief Kim Bong Sik, who's back in Seoul now.
سأثق فقط بالزعيم كيم بونج سيك، الذي عاد إلى سيول الآن.
Why would you trust me? Don't trust anyone.
لماذا تثق بي؟ لا تثق بأحد.
Goodness, you're hurting my feelings here.
ياإلهي، أنت تجرح مشاعري هنا.
You don't even trust me?
أنت لا تثق بي حتى؟
You little...
أنت قليلا...
By the way, the Suseong-dong case in Gangnam.
بالمناسبة، قضية سوسونغ دونغ في جانج نام.
Who is the victim?
من هو الضحية؟
Those at Gangnam Police Station are keeping it on the hush-hush.
أولئك الموجودون في مركز شرطة جانج نام يلتزمون الصمت.
Hey, today is my first day.
مهلا، اليوم هو أول يوم لي.
You must've heard something, even just in passing.
لا بد أنك سمعت شيئًا ما، حتى ولو بشكل عابر.
Can I please eat first?
هل يمكنني من فضلك تناول الطعام أولاً؟
Captain Yoon, you're here.
كابتن يون، أنت هنا.
- I heard you asked for me. - What? You came alone?
- سمعت أنك طلبت مني. - ماذا؟ جئت وحدك؟
Is Bong Sik not at his desk?
هل بونج سيك ليس في مكتبه؟
Detectives must be ready to mobilize at all times.
يجب أن يكون المحققون على استعداد للتعبئة في جميع الأوقات.
Today is his first day, and we can't even reach him?
اليوم هو يومه الأول، ولا نستطيع حتى الوصول إليه؟
Darn it.
الرتق.
We need you to take on this case.
نحن بحاجة لك أن تأخذ على هذه القضية.
The victim is Han Seok Hoon,
الضحية هو هان سيوك هون
an economics professor at Hankuk University.
أستاذ الاقتصاد في جامعة هانكوك.
He and his wife were murdered in their home two weeks ago.
لقد قُتل هو وزوجته في منزلهما منذ أسبوعين.
(Murder of Elderly Couple in Suseong-dong)
(مقتل زوجين مسنين في سوسونغ دونغ)
We need you to investigate it.
نحن بحاجة لك للتحقيق في الأمر.
This case belongs to Gangnam Police Station.
هذه القضية تخص مركز شرطة جانجنام.
It does fall under their jurisdiction,
فهو يقع ضمن اختصاصهم،
but he's related to someone who is very high up.
لكنه مرتبط بشخص رفيع المستوى.
I was asked to look into it quietly,
لقد طلب مني أن أنظر إليه بهدوء،
so that's all I know.
هذا كل ما أعرفه.
But I think they're struggling to find leads.
لكنني أعتقد أنهم يكافحون للعثور على خيوط.
How do I find a phone number?
كيف يمكنني العثور على رقم الهاتف؟
I think the reporters already caught a whiff of it.
أعتقد أن المراسلين قد اكتشفوا بالفعل نفحة منه.
The higher-ups want us...
كبار المسؤولين يريدون منا...
to prevent further media coverage and investigate it swiftly.
لمنع المزيد من التغطية الإعلامية والتحقيق فيها بسرعة.
Everyone at Gangnam Police Station will help you out.
الجميع في مركز شرطة جانج نام سيساعدك.
Okay.
تمام.
- I'll be off, then. - Okay.
- سأخرج إذن. - تمام.
There, I found it.
هناك، وجدت ذلك.
Look at this.
أنظر إلى هذا.
This punk, Kim Bong Sik. He's not picking up.
هذا الشرير، كيم بونج سيك. انه لا يلتقط.
Is it an important case?
هل هي قضية مهمة؟
All homicide cases are equally important.
جميع قضايا القتل لها نفس القدر من الأهمية.
That's true.
هذا صحيح.
Why are we investigating Gangnam Police Station's case?
لماذا نحقق في قضية مركز شرطة جانجنام؟
We should go there to find out more.
يجب أن نذهب إلى هناك لمعرفة المزيد.
- Chief Kim still isn't at his desk? - No.
- الرئيس كيم لا يزال ليس في مكتبه؟ - لا.
People really don't change.
الناس حقا لا يتغيرون.
(September 29, 2003)
(29 سبتمبر 2003)
Are we leaving now? Just the two of us?
هل سنغادر الآن؟ فقط نحن الاثنان؟
(Gungok-dong, Jongno)
(جونجوك دونج، جونجنو)
(September 24, 2003)
(24 سبتمبر 2003)
No, please...
لا من فضلك...
(Victim Han Seok Hoon, economics professor)
(الضحية هان سيوك هون، أستاذ الاقتصاد)
Darn it, this scumbag...
تبا لك أيها الحقير...
(Murder of Elderly Couple in Suseong-dong)
(مقتل زوجين مسنين في سوسونغ دونغ)
The victims of the murder of the couple in their 60s in Suseong-dong.
ضحايا مقتل الزوجين في الستينيات من العمر في سوسونغ دونغ.
Han Seok Hoon,
هان سيوك هون,
a Hankuk University professor, and his wife.
أستاذ بجامعة هانكوك وزوجته.
I bet there's something about Professor Han Seok Hoon.
أراهن أن هناك شيئًا ما بشأن البروفيسور هان سيوك هون.
Gosh, seriously.
يا إلهي، على محمل الجد.
I told you not to say the victim's name.
أخبرتك ألا تقول إسم الضحية
Come on. You need to give me something to write about.
تعال. عليك أن تعطيني شيئا لأكتب عنه.
Loyalty isn't a one-way street.
الولاء ليس طريقًا ذو اتجاه واحد.
They've been preserving the scene for over two weeks now.
لقد تم الحفاظ على المشهد لأكثر من أسبوعين الآن.
There's definitely something.
هناك بالتأكيد شيء ما.
Will you really not tell me anything?
هل حقا لن تخبرني بأي شيء؟
Over here.
هنا.
Good day.
يوم جيد.
I'm Yoon Tae Gu from the Seoul HQ.
أنا يون تاي جو من المقر الرئيسي في سيول.
- This is... - Nam Il Young, also from HQ.
- هذا... - نام إيل يونغ، من المقر الرئيسي أيضًا.
Yes, they called me. This way, please.
نعم لقد اتصلوا بي. بهذه الطريقة من فضلك.
- Okay. - Hey, tidy up here.
- تمام. - مهلا، مرتبة هنا.
(Do Not Enter)
(لا تدخل)
There was cash lying around, but he didn't even touch it.
كان هناك نقود ملقاة حوله، لكنه لم يلمسها حتى.
They think it's an act of resentment masked as a burglary.
يعتقدون أنه عمل من أعمال الاستياء مقنع كعملية سطو.
It's clean.
انها نظيفة.
It means the victims were overpowered...
يعني أن الضحايا قد تم التغلب عليهم...
without any sort of resistance.
دون أي نوع من المقاومة.
If they had resisted, the blood would have splattered...
لو قاوموا لتناثرت الدماء...
to the ceiling because his weapon was swinging around.
إلى السقف لأن سلاحه كان يتأرجح.
You'll see that the victims' bodies are clean...
سترون أن أجساد الضحايا نظيفة..
with no sign of defense when you get to the morgue later.
بدون أي علامة دفاع عندما تصل إلى المشرحة لاحقًا.
Gosh, I don't know what this horrifying guy hit them with.
يا إلهي، لا أعرف ما الذي ضربهم به هذا الرجل المرعب.
We're trying our best to find out but weren't able to identify it yet.
نحن نبذل قصارى جهدنا لمعرفة ذلك ولكننا لم نتمكن من التعرف عليه بعد.
He came into a rich house like this...
لقد جاء إلى منزل غني مثل هذا ...
and he didn't touch the cash but only pretended to look for it.
ولم يلمس النقود بل تظاهر بالبحث عنها فقط.
Do you think he had a grudge against them?
هل تعتقد أنه كان لديه ضغينة ضدهم؟
We looked into that, but that seems highly unlikely.
لقد بحثنا في ذلك، ولكن يبدو أن هذا غير مرجح إلى حد كبير.
Both husband and wife had a great reputation.
يتمتع كل من الزوج والزوجة بسمعة طيبة.
Their identities are accompanied by their social position.
هوياتهم مصحوبة بوضعهم الاجتماعي.
So they may have incurred a grudge from someone without knowing.
لذلك ربما يكون قد أصابهم ضغينة من شخص ما دون أن يعلموا.
You're saying it may be the doings of an acquaintance holding a grudge?
هل تقول أنه قد يكون من أفعال أحد معارفك الذي يحمل ضغينة؟
Shall we start by investigating around the school?
هل نبدأ بالتحقيق حول المدرسة؟
We already did.
لقد فعلنا ذلك بالفعل.
Even if we consider this to be an act of resentment...
حتى لو اعتبرنا هذا عملاً من أعمال الاستياء.
his method is too bold and violent.
طريقته جريئة وعنيفة للغاية.
Overkilling is common amongst murder targeting acquaintances.
الإفراط في القتل أمر شائع بين جرائم القتل التي تستهدف المعارف.
I doubt that a mentally ill person...
أشك أن الشخص مريض نفسيا..
could have casually walked into a house like this.
كان من الممكن أن يدخل عرضًا إلى منزل مثل هذا.
Could you please give us the list of acquaintances you interviewed?
هل يمكنك أن تعطينا قائمة المعارف التي أجريت معهم مقابلات؟
Yes, I will.
نعم سأفعل.
Once you get the list, check to see if there's anyone...
بمجرد حصولك على القائمة، تحقق لمعرفة ما إذا كان هناك أي شخص...
with records of previous convictions and mental illness.
مع سجلات الإدانات السابقة والأمراض العقلية.
Yes, ma'am.
نعم سيدتي.
Why did a detective from Seoul HQ come to a case in Gangnam?
لماذا جاء محقق من المقر الرئيسي لسيول إلى قضية في جانج نام؟
Yes, sir?
نعم يا سيدي؟
Hey! Didn't I tell you to release first and fact check later?
يا! ألم أطلب منك إطلاق سراحك أولاً والتحقق من الحقائق لاحقًا؟
An article has been released...
لقد تم نشر مقال...
identifying the Suseong-dong victim as Professor Han Seok Hoon!
التعرف على ضحية سوسونغ دونغ على أنها البروفيسور هان سيوك هون!
What?
ماذا؟
You try to be respectful, conscientious, and even loyal.
تحاول أن تكون محترمًا وضميرًا وحتى مخلصًا.
So when do you plan on trying to get an exclusive?
إذن متى تخطط لمحاولة الحصول على حصري؟
Who wrote that article?
من كتب تلك المقالة؟
Who do you think? It's Im Moo Sik, of course.
من برأيك؟ إنه إيم مو سيك، بالطبع.
Gosh, that darn punk!
يا إلهي، هذا الشرير الرتق!
Let's hurry on over. Gosh!
دعونا نسرع. يا إلهي!
(Chief Kim Bong Sik, Special Crime Squad)
(الزعيم كيم بونج سيك، فرقة الجريمة الخاصة)
Thank you, Bong Sik.
شكرا لك، بونج سيك.
Oh, boy.
يا فتى.
Kook Young Soo.
كوك يونج سو.
(Senior Inspector, Kook Young Soo)
(كبير المفتشين، كوك يونغ سو)
Gosh, so this is it.
يا إلهي، هذا هو الأمر.
(Investigation Record)
(محضر التحقيق)
Having us waste our time by giving us useless things to do.
جعلنا نضيع وقتنا بإعطائنا أشياء عديمة الفائدة للقيام بها.
The things these higher-ups come up with from their heads...
الأشياء التي يأتي بها هؤلاء الكبار من رؤوسهم...
What about our heads?
وماذا عن رؤوسنا؟
I meant it's always such useful things.
أعني أنها دائما مثل هذه الأشياء المفيدة.
What's with this case report? You barely even tried.
ما قصة تقرير الحالة هذا؟ أنت بالكاد حاولت.
Be more descriptive.
كن أكثر وصفًا.
(Murder of Elderly Couple in Suseong-dong)
(مقتل زوجين مسنين في سوسونغ دونغ)
Did you talk to Captain Yoon?
هل تحدثت مع الكابتن يون؟
I'm sure she's doing just fine.
أنا متأكد من أنها بخير.
It's best for superiors to just stand back and do nothing.
من الأفضل للرؤساء أن يقفوا في الخلف ولا يفعلوا شيئًا.
Are you talking about me?
هل تتحدث عني؟
Gosh, of course not.
يا إلهي، بالطبع لا.
Some punk must have leaked the case.
لا بد أن بعض الأشرار قد سرب القضية.
The reporters are already on it.
الصحفيين بالفعل على ذلك.
Those darn reporters. They sure are fast.
هؤلاء المراسلين الرتق. من المؤكد أنهم سريعون.
Seriously?
بجد؟
They're coming!
إنهم قادمون!
Are there still no leads to Professor Han Seok Hoon's case?
ألا يوجد حتى الآن أي دليل على قضية البروفيسور هان سيوك هون؟
It was out of resentment, right?
لقد كان ذلك بسبب الاستياء، أليس كذلك؟
Come on! Are you done interviewing? Do you have a suspect?
تعال! هل انتهيت من المقابلة؟ هل لديك مشتبه به؟
Are you sure it wasn't out of resentment?
هل أنت متأكد من أنه لم يكن من باب الاستياء؟
Are you certain it was an acquaintance's doing?
هل أنت متأكد من أنه كان من فعل أحد معارفك؟
Answer us, please!
أجب علينا من فضلك!
- Please tell us! - Excuse me!
- من فضلك اخبرنا! - اعذرني!
(Hwang Dae Sun, 2nd Interview Report)
(هوانج داي صن، تقرير المقابلة الثانية)
What was the purpose of carving out the flesh...
ما هو الهدف من نحت الجسد...
after the victim's death?
بعد وفاة الضحية؟
It looks like you'll have homework tonight.
يبدو أنه سيكون لديك واجب منزلي الليلة.
You're still thinking about Hwang Dae Sun, aren't you?
مازلت تفكر في هوانج داي صن، أليس كذلك؟
You know me.
أنت تعرفني.
Why don't we start our meeting?
لماذا لا نبدأ اجتماعنا؟
Serial murders can be categorized into these three things.
يمكن تصنيف جرائم القتل التسلسلية إلى هذه الأشياء الثلاثة.
A psychological cooling-off period.
فترة تهدئة نفسية.
Crime committed against a stranger, for the sole purpose of murder.
الجريمة المرتكبة ضد شخص غريب لغرض وحيد هو القتل.
Murdering 3 or more people, in 3 or more locations.
قتل 3 أشخاص أو أكثر في 3 مواقع أو أكثر.
Out of all the prisoners we've met until now,
من بين جميع السجناء الذين التقينا بهم حتى الآن،
Hwang Dae Sun is closest...
هوانج داي صن هو الأقرب...
to the serial murderer category that we've been researching.
إلى فئة القاتل المتسلسل التي كنا نبحث عنها.
He can be viewed as a serial killer since he killed three people.
يمكن اعتباره قاتلًا متسلسلًا لأنه قتل ثلاثة أشخاص.
But to be exact, he ended up with three victims...
لكن على وجه الدقة، انتهى به الأمر مع ثلاثة ضحايا...
from two different cases.
من حالتين مختلفتين.
He killed one out of impulse.
لقد قتل واحدًا بدافع الاندفاع.
He may have been planning on murdering...
ربما كان يخطط لقتل...
but it was one that derailed from his plans.
لكنها كانت التي خرجت عن خططه.
I see two were raped then murdered and the other was a man.
أرى أن اثنين منهم اغتصبا ثم قُتلا والآخر رجل.
He had been drinking when committing both cases.
وكان يشرب الخمر عند ارتكاب الحالتين.
The man was the second victim's boyfriend.
وكان الرجل هو صديق الضحية الثانية.
Then the boyfriend was the target of his impulsive crime?
إذن كان الصديق هو هدف جريمته المتهورة؟
Exactly.
بالضبط.
He was murdered...
لقد تم قتله...
when he came over to see his girlfriend and witnessed the rape.
عندما جاء لرؤية صديقته وشهد الاغتصاب.
All three victims were murdered while he was under the influence...
لقد قُتل الضحايا الثلاثة بينما كان تحت تأثير الكحول...
it must have been categorized as an unsystematic crime.
يجب أن يتم تصنيفها على أنها جريمة غير منهجية.
Just because he murdered when under the influence...
فقط لأنه قتل وهو تحت تأثير الكحول...
doesn't mean that it was an unsystematic crime.
لا يعني أنها كانت جريمة غير منهجية.
An unsystematic crime...
جريمة غير منظمة..
is when the culprit becomes confused while committing the crime.
هو عندما يرتبك الجاني أثناء ارتكاب الجريمة.
In the case of Hwang Dae Sun, we can interpret his acts of...
في حالة هوانج داي سون، يمكننا تفسير تصرفاته...
binding and carving out the skin, as abnormal sexual behaviors.
ربط ونحت الجلد، كسلوك جنسي غير طبيعي.
So it doesn't add up perfectly.
لذلك لا تضيف ما يصل تماما.
If you look at it according to the FBI's categories of crime...
إذا نظرت إليها وفقًا لفئات الجرائم التي وضعها مكتب التحقيقات الفيدرالي...
a systematic type is someone who has problems with their personality.
النوع المنهجي هو الشخص الذي يعاني من مشاكل في شخصيته.
An unsystematic type...
نوع غير نظامي..
is categorized as someone delusional or schizophrenic.
يتم تصنيفه على أنه شخص موهوم أو انفصام الشخصية.
With that in mind, Hwang Dae Sun...
مع أخذ ذلك في الاعتبار، هوانغ داي سون...
isn't someone who has a mental illness...
ليس من يعاني من مرض نفسي..
but a systematic type with a personality disorder.
لكنه نوع منهجي يعاني من اضطراب في الشخصية.
Gosh, this is really difficult.
يا إلهي، هذا صعب حقًا.
In the case of Hwang Dae Sun, he showed systematic behavior...
وفي حالة هوانج داي سون، فقد أظهر سلوكًا منظمًا...
in how he searched for his victim, planned, and bound them using tools.
في كيفية بحثه عن ضحيته والتخطيط لها وتقييدها باستخدام الأدوات.
I understand when you tell me...
أفهم عندما تقول لي..
I think the process of reasoning is always very difficult.
أعتقد أن عملية التفكير تكون دائمًا صعبة للغاية.
All right then.
حسنًا إذن.
I think the reason for Hwang Dae Sun's case is...
أعتقد أن السبب وراء قضية هوانج داي سون هو...
this one. Killing more than three.
هذا. مقتل أكثر من ثلاثة.
Okay.
تمام.
But I think it's more accurate to label it a rape and murder case...
لكن أعتقد أنه من الأدق وصفها بقضية اغتصاب وقتل..
which has more continuity to it.
والذي لديه المزيد من الاستمرارية لذلك.
Right, since he had a sexual purpose to it.
صحيح، لأنه كان لديه غرض جنسي لذلك.
Right, but there was a bigger chance of him becoming...
صحيح، ولكن كانت هناك فرصة أكبر ليصبح...
a serial killer like in our study if he hadn't been caught.
قاتل متسلسل كما هو الحال في دراستنا إذا لم يتم القبض عليه.
I was shocked when I heard he killed animals as a kid.
لقد صدمت عندما سمعت أنه كان يقتل الحيوانات عندما كان طفلاً.
It's a classic feature that a serial killer has.
إنها ميزة كلاسيكية يمتلكها القاتل المتسلسل.
He didn't have a cooling-off period though.
He didn't have a cooling-off period though.
(A psychological cooling-off period)
(A psychological cooling-off period)
The culprit behind the Suseong-dong murder case of the old couple...
الجاني وراء قضية مقتل الزوجين المسنين في سوسونغ دونغ...
in their 60s which happened in Gangnam on the 10th...
في الستينات من عمرهم والذي حدث في جانج نام في العاشر من الشهر...
has yet to be caught.
لم يتم القبض عليه بعد.
People are shocked after the victim was identified...
والناس في حالة صدمة بعد التعرف على الضحية..
as Hankuk University's Professor Han Seok Hoon.
as Hankuk University's Professor Han Seok Hoon.
Not only did Professor Han...
Not only did Professor Han...
teach economics at the university,
teach economics at the university,
but he also appeared on TV often to give his economical insights.
لكنه ظهر أيضًا على شاشة التلفزيون كثيرًا لتقديم أفكاره الاقتصادية.
His bold attitude led to his popularity.
His bold attitude led to his popularity.
But does there always have to be a psychological cooling-off period?
ولكن هل يجب أن تكون هناك دائما فترة تهدئة نفسية؟
Serial killers feel the highest form of pleasure...
القتلة المتسلسلون يشعرون بأعلى أشكال المتعة...
in the pure act of killing.
in the pure act of killing.
Once that feeling ends,
وبمجرد أن ينتهي هذا الشعور،
they look for another victim who will satisfy their need.
يبحثون عن ضحية أخرى تلبي حاجتهم.
To put it simply, a cooling-off period...
To put it simply, a cooling-off period...
is a period where their sense of fulfillment and satisfaction...
هي الفترة التي يشعرون فيها بالرضا والرضا.
from the murder continues to last.
from the murder continues to last.
Once that psychological satisfaction comes to an end...
وبمجرد أن ينتهي هذا الرضا النفسي..
they'll move on to the next murder.
they'll move on to the next murder.
Then what about Hwang Dae Sun?
Then what about Hwang Dae Sun?
In the case of Hwang Dae Sun,
In the case of Hwang Dae Sun,
we can't view those periods as a cooling-off period...
لا يمكننا أن ننظر إلى تلك الفترات على أنها فترة تهدئة...
since he was under the influence for all the cases.
لأنه كان تحت التأثير في جميع الحالات.
But the fact that they murder again once the cooling-off period ends...
لكن حقيقة أنهم يقتلون مرة أخرى بمجرد انتهاء فترة التهدئة...
is so horrifying.
أمر مرعب جدا.
Thankfully, in the Republic of Korea,
Thankfully, in the Republic of Korea,
there still hasn't been a serial murder case...
there still hasn't been a serial murder case...
with the purpose of murder followed by a cooling-off period.
بغرض القتل تليها فترة تهدئة.
It's all just speculation.
It's all just speculation.
You wanted to catch guys like this during your ten years, right?
لقد أردت القبض على رجال مثل هؤلاء خلال السنوات العشر التي قضيتها، أليس كذلك؟
You said you didn't find any injuries on the back...
قلت أنك لم تجد أي إصابات في الظهر...
from either of them, right?
from either of them, right?
Right, I didn't find any.
Right, I didn't find any.
It looks clean, don't you think?
It looks clean, don't you think?
Drop me off at the office, please.
Drop me off at the office, please.
You're not going home?
أنت لن تذهب إلى المنزل؟
No, I want to organize my thoughts.
No, I want to organize my thoughts.
You can head home first. Good job today.
يمكنك التوجه إلى المنزل أولاً. عمل جيد اليوم.
No, I want to stop by Gangnam Police Station first.
لا، أريد التوقف عند مركز شرطة جانجنام أولاً.
I heard it's a mess over there right now.
I heard it's a mess over there right now.
(Scientific Investigations Team)
(Scientific Investigations Team)
Which team was Gangnam's Professor Han case handed over to?
إلى أي فريق تم تسليم قضية جانجنام البروفيسور هان؟
Special Crime Squad's Team Two.
Special Crime Squad's Team Two.
Hello? Yes.
مرحبًا؟ نعم.
(Forensics)
(الطب الشرعي)
Footprints?
آثار أقدام؟
Yes, all right. I'll get back to you.
نعم، حسنًا. سأعود إليك.
- It's Jongno Police Station. - Okay.
- It's Jongno Police Station. - تمام.
The Gungok-dong case they sent in last week...
The Gungok-dong case they sent in last week...
They want us to return the ex-convict's data...
They want us to return the ex-convict's data...
which included his footprints and a few pieces of evidence.
والتي تضمنت آثار أقدامه وبعض الأدلة.
- Shall I bring it over? - Yes.
- هل أحضره؟ - نعم.
(Suseong-dong Case Footprints)
(Suseong-dong Case Footprints)
- Here you go. - Thanks.
- هنا تذهب. - شكرًا.
Hold on.
يتمسك.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
Don't these look similar?
Don't these look similar?
I think they do.
أعتقد أنهم يفعلون.
You only thought about Hwang Dae Sun for a while.
لقد فكرت في هوانج داي صن لفترة من الوقت فقط.
- Good job. - Thank you.
- أحسنت. - شكرًا لك.
(Hwang Dae Sun, 2nd Interview Report)
(هوانج داي صن، تقرير المقابلة الثانية)
Good job. Let's go now.
عمل جيد. دعنا نذهب الآن.
You can head home.
يمكنك التوجه إلى المنزل.
I have a bunch of unfinished work because of this report.
لدي مجموعة من الأعمال غير المكتملة بسبب هذا التقرير.
My gosh, you're unbelievable.
يا إلهي، أنت لا تصدق.
What's the word for this? Work-a-hill?
ما هي الكلمة المناسبة لهذا؟ العمل في التل؟
- It's "holic." - A workaholic!
- إنها "مقدسة". - مدمن عمل!
I'll get going.
سأذهب.
Jung Chu Chu! How about a glass of soju and beer?
جونغ تشو تشو! ماذا عن كوب من السوجو والبيرة؟
Sounds great!
يبدو عظيما!
- Hang in there! - All right. Bye.
- شنق هناك! - حسنًا. الوداع.
- Hang in there! - I will.
- شنق هناك! - أنا سوف.
(Gungok-dong Family Murder Case, September 24, 2003)
(قضية مقتل عائلة جونجوك دونج، 24 سبتمبر 2003)
(Unidentified weapon)
(سلاح مجهول)
Both victims do not have...
كلا الضحيتين ليس لهما...
any defense marks or signs of resistance.
أي علامات دفاعية أو علامات مقاومة.
The culprit beat the victims without giving them a moment...
الجاني يضرب الضحايا دون أن يمنحهم لحظة..
to protect themselves.
لحماية أنفسهم.
(September 24, 2003, Gungok-dong)
(24 سبتمبر 2003، جونجوك دونج)
A type of systematic crime committed according to a plan.
نوع من الجرائم الممنهجة التي ترتكب وفق خطة.
The crime is too cruel and daring to conclude...
الجريمة قاسية جدًا وجريئة للغاية.
that it was done by an acquaintance.
أنه تم ذلك من قبل أحد معارفه.
(Jinjung-dong, Gangnam)
(جينجونج دونج، جانج نام)
The culprit did not take any money or valuables.
ولم يأخذ الجاني أي أموال أو أشياء ثمينة.
Who is it?
من هذا؟
(Disguised as robbery...)
(تنكر في صورة سرقة...)
(Theft, valuables, not taken. Holding a grudge?)
(السرقة، الأشياء الثمينة، لم يتم أخذها. هل تحمل ضغينة؟)
- Who is it? - Is somebody here?
- من هو؟ - هل شخص ما هنا؟
Yes, but I don't hear anything.
Yes, but I don't hear anything.
It must be a prank.
يجب أن تكون مزحة.
Goodnight.
طاب مساؤك.
That's odd. Okay. Goodnight.
هذا غريب. تمام. طاب مساؤك.
Night.
ليلة.
(Disguised as robbery, presumed as an acquaintance with a grudge)
(متنكر في زي سرقة، مفترض في هيئة أحد المعارف ولديه ضغينة)
But is there someone...
ولكن هل هناك شخص...
who is an ex-convict around Professor Han?
who is an ex-convict around Professor Han?
Is this a way of expressing...
Is this a way of expressing...
the culprit's emotions caused by a grudge they hold?
عواطف الجاني الناجمة عن ضغينة لديهم؟
(Gungok-dong, Jongno)
(جونجوك دونج، جونجنو)
(Do Not Enter, Under Investigation)
(ممنوع الدخول، قيد التحقيق)
(15 Gungok-dong)
(15 جونجوك دونج)
(Song Young Chul, Lee Geum Soon)
(Song Young Chul, Lee Geum Soon)
(Case Report)
(تقرير الحالة)
(Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency)
(وكالة شرطة العاصمة سيول)
Are you coming to work just now?
Are you coming to work just now?
Yes.
نعم.
What happened at the crime scene yesterday?
What happened at the crime scene yesterday?
I thought you weren't interested. Are you actually curious?
I thought you weren't interested. Are you actually curious?
I'll tell you once we're inside.
I'll tell you once we're inside.
You got a lot bolder, Tae Gu.
You got a lot bolder, Tae Gu.
You still have that feisty charm.
You still have that feisty charm.
I do not want your evaluation of my charms.
I do not want your evaluation of my charms.
I hope we can just carry out our duties...
I hope we can just carry out our duties...
without getting in each other's ways.
without getting in each other's ways.
You know how important teamwork is...
You know how important teamwork is...
when it comes to violent crimes.
when it comes to violent crimes.
How can you only do your duty and end it there?
How can you only do your duty and end it there?
Tae Gu, do you still have a grudge against me?
Tae Gu, do you still have a grudge against me?
A grudge?
ضغينة؟
You're quite delusional.
أنت موهوم تمامًا.
I do not have any feelings about you.
ليس لدي أي مشاعر تجاهك.
I'm sorry about that.
أنا آسف لذلك.
But everyone already knows that I'm a big jerk.
ولكن الجميع يعرف بالفعل أنني أحمق كبير.
Right?
يمين؟
I was also aware of how you were a jerk too.
كنت أيضًا على علم بمدى كونك أحمقًا أيضًا.
Isn't that so?
أليس كذلك؟
Let's go inside.
دعنا نذهب إلى الداخل.
I should not stop the ace of the Special Crime Squad.
لا ينبغي لي أن أوقف قائد فرقة الجرائم الخاصة.
Shall I, then?
هل يجب علي إذن؟
Gosh, heartburn.
يا إلهي، حرقة المعدة.
You still think you can do this job by keeping loyalty...
ما زلت تعتقد أنه يمكنك القيام بهذه المهمة من خلال الحفاظ على الولاء...
even after three years you spent here.
حتى بعد ثلاث سنوات قضيتها هنا.
What should I do with you?
ماذا يجب أن أفعل معك؟
You know how strict...
هل تعلم مدى صرامة...
Detective Kang and Park are.
المحقق كانغ وبارك.
I'm sure Moo Sik...
أنا متأكد من أن مو سيك...
won't get any information from Gangnam Police Station anymore.
لن تحصل على أي معلومات من مركز شرطة جانجنام بعد الآن.
Detective Park isn't the only detective there.
المحقق بارك ليس المحقق الوحيد هناك.
If anyone leaks information to Daehan Daily,
إذا قام أي شخص بتسريب المعلومات إلى صحيفة دايهان اليومية،
it all turns into Im Moo Sik's article,
كل هذا يتحول إلى مقالة Im Moo Sik،
while you're sitting around depending on Detective Park.
بينما أنت جالس بالاعتماد على المحقق بارك.
Moo Sik...
مو سيك...
even steals articles from juniors?
حتى يسرق المقالات من الصغار؟
Man, talk about lack of conscience.
يا رجل، تحدث عن قلة الضمير.
Yes, conscience.
نعم الضمير.
You'll starve to death after keeping your conscience.
سوف تتضور جوعا حتى الموت بعد الحفاظ على ضميرك.
I've been running around a lot trying not to starve to death.
لقد كنت أركض كثيرًا محاولًا ألا أموت جوعًا.
Okay, sure. You work so hard. You're very commendable, aren't you?
حسنا، بالتأكيد. أنت تعمل بجد. أنت جدير بالثناء للغاية، أليس كذلك؟
My diligent boss is doing a great job at making me slave away.
يقوم مديري المجتهد بعمل رائع في جعلني عبدًا بعيدًا.
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
Go out and find an item that'll become as good a story...
اخرج وابحث عن العنصر الذي سيصبح قصة جيدة...
as the one you had stolen.
كالتي سرقتها
It wasn't ours anyway. What do you mean it was stolen?
لم يكن لنا على أي حال. ماذا تقصد بأنها مسروقة؟
It's Detective Park.
إنه المحقق بارك
Another case at Gangnam Police Station.
حالة أخرى في مركز شرطة جانجنام.
- Again? - Yes.
- مرة أخرى؟ - نعم.
Hey, Reporter Choi, keep it up. Run!
مرحبًا، أيها الصحفي تشوي، استمر في ذلك. يجري!
Forget all about your conscience and loyalty!
ننسى كل شيء عن ضميرك والولاء!
Reporter Choi, get us just one good story!
المراسل تشوي، أحضر لنا قصة جيدة واحدة فقط!
Keep up the good work, then.
استمروا في العمل الجيد، إذن.
Man, I like how big this office is.
يا رجل، يعجبني حجم هذا المكتب.
Are you satisfied with the result of your first duty on the job?
هل أنت راض عن نتيجة واجبك الأول في الوظيفة؟
Captain Kook already did all the work.
قام الكابتن كوك بكل العمل بالفعل.
If I just sit there taking up someone's spot,
إذا جلست هناك لأخذ مكان شخص ما،
think of how awkward I'd feel.
فكر في مدى شعوري بالحرج.
So what will they do with all that information?
فماذا سيفعلون بكل هذه المعلومات؟
No idea.
لا فكرة.
He said he'll use it as his pillow or something.
قال إنه سيستخدمها كوسادة له أو شيء من هذا القبيل.
I'm sure Captain Kook will make good use of everything.
أنا متأكد من أن الكابتن كوك سيستفيد من كل شيء.
Make sure you check and take everything as needed!
تأكد من فحص واتخاذ كل شيء حسب الحاجة!
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
- نعم يا سيدي. - نعم يا سيدي.
- In Tak. - Hey, Young Soo.
- في تاك. - مهلا، يونغ سو.
Is something going on?
هل هناك شيء يحدث؟
Gangnam Station needed backup,
محطة جانجنام بحاجة إلى نسخة احتياطية،
so we're all going to Jinjung-dong.
لذلك نحن جميعا ذاهبون إلى Jinjung-dong.
What about you?
ماذا عنك؟
I have to check some footprints.
لا بد لي من التحقق من بعض آثار الأقدام.
I see. Keep it up.
أرى. استمر.
- Okay. - Wait.
- تمام. - انتظر.
- To the Behavioral Analysis Team? - I'm fine. Get back to work.
- إلى فريق التحليل السلوكي؟ - أنا بخير. العودة إلى العمل.
I'll go with you.
سأذهب معك.
Hey, I'm still going strong.
مهلا، ما زلت قويا.
You look busy. Get back to work.
تبدو مشغولا. العودة إلى العمل.
- Hey. - Bye.
- يا. - الوداع.
- Are you sure? - Yes.
- هل أنت متأكد؟ - نعم.
If you get stuck, feel free to bring it to us.
إذا واجهتك مشكلة، فلا تتردد في إحضارها إلينا.
- Bye. - Be careful!
- الوداع. - احرص!
Darn it.
الرتق.
- Over here. - Salute.
- هنا. - تحية.
Grab everything there.
الاستيلاء على كل شيء هناك.
- Yes, there. - News flash.
- نعم هناك. - فلاش الأخبار.
Today afternoon in Jinjung-dong, Gangnam-gu,
بعد ظهر اليوم في جينجونج دونج، جانج نام غو،
a woman in her 50s was found dead...
العثور على امرأة في الخمسينات من عمرها مقتولة...
after being struck by a blunt weapon.
بعد تعرضه للضرب بسلاح حاد.
The police were dispatched for an investigation...
وأرسلت الشرطة للتحقيق..
after a report made by Lee, the maid,
بعد بلاغ قدمته لي الخادمة،
who saw the collapsed victim in her home in Jinjung-dong.
التي رأت الضحية المنهارة في منزلها في جينجونج دونج.
Can you share something with us?
هل يمكنك مشاركة شيء معنا؟
Gangnam Police Station said...
وقال مركز شرطة جانج نام...
the culprit of today's Jinjung-dong incident...
الجاني في حادثة جينجونغ دونغ اليوم...
and the Suseong-dong incident is...
وحادثة سوسونغ دونغ هي...
Chief Heo, what on earth is going on?
أيها الرئيس هيو، ماذا يحدث بحق السماء؟
I told you to investigate this quietly.
قلت لك أن تحقق في هذا بهدوء.
Why is the case blowing up?
لماذا تفجرت القضية؟
Captain Yoon and Detective Nam are at the scene right now.
الكابتن يون والمحقق نام موجودان في مكان الحادث الآن.
Let's hear from them once they return.
دعونا نسمع منهم بمجرد عودتهم.
Good grief.
حزن جيد.
Where's Kim Bong Sik?
أين كيم بونج سيك؟
No idea. But he'll crawl back...
لا فكرة. لكنه سوف يتراجع..
if he thinks this will affect his performance.
إذا كان يعتقد أن هذا سيؤثر على أدائه.
That's his deal.
هذه هي صفقته.
Look at how big this case has become.
انظروا إلى مدى حجم هذه القضية.
We might end up taking over both of these cases.
قد ينتهي بنا الأمر إلى تولي هاتين الحالتين.
Tell me about it.
أخبرني عن ذلك.
These reporters already began to say...
لقد بدأ هؤلاء المراسلون بالفعل بالقول...
that they're related or something.
أنهم مرتبطون أو شيء من هذا.
I have a bad feeling about this. We can't let this happen.
لدي شعور سيء حول هذا. لا يمكننا أن ندع هذا يحدث.
Okay. Who is it?
تمام. من هذا؟
Excuse me.
اعذرني.
Hey.
يا.
- Hello. - Hello.
- مرحبًا. - مرحبًا.
What brings you here?
ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا؟
I found something weird. I wanted your opinion on this.
لقد وجدت شيئا غريبا. أردت رأيك في هذا.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
They are both hiking shoes.
كلاهما حذاء المشي لمسافات طويلة.
- Yes. - What about them?
- نعم. - وماذا عنهم؟
This one is from Suseong-dong, Gangnam.
هذا من سوسونج دونج، جانج نام.
And this one is from Gungok-dong, Jongno.
وهذا من جونجوك دونج، جونجنو.
They match, right?
إنهم متطابقون، أليس كذلك؟
They are from different districts, but it's the same culprit?
إنهم من مناطق مختلفة، ولكن هو نفس الجاني؟
(A posh residential house in Gungok-dong)
(منزل سكني فاخر في جونجوك دونج)
My mom cooked breakfast for me, and I ate it and went to work.
أعدت لي أمي الفطور، فأكلته وذهبت إلى العمل.
When I called, she didn't answer.
عندما اتصلت، لم ترد.
So I came home and...
لذلك عدت إلى المنزل و...
Can you think of anyone who held grudges against her?
هل يمكنك التفكير في أي شخص يحمل ضغينة ضدها؟
Or did she have any money problems?
أو هل كان لديها أي مشاكل مالية؟
None.
لا أحد.
Did she ever sound upset on the phone?
هل بدت منزعجة على الهاتف من قبل؟
No.
لا.
Hey.
مهلا.
("A Woman in Her 50s Found Dead in Jinjung-dong")
("العثور على امرأة في الخمسينيات من عمرها ميتة في جينجونغ دونغ")
What? There was another case in Jinjung-dong.
ماذا؟ كانت هناك حالة أخرى في جينجونج دونج.
- What? - Look at this.
- ماذا؟ - أنظر إلى هذا.
Yes. I'm reading it now.
نعم. أنا أقرأه الآن.
"A woman in her 50s from a 2-story house in Jinjung-dong..."
"امرأة في الخمسينيات من عمرها من منزل مكون من طابقين في جينجونغ دونغ..."
"was found dead from blunt force trauma."
"تم العثور عليه ميتا نتيجة لصدمة قوية."
(Blunt force trauma in the head)
(صدمة قوية في الرأس)
So was the victim in Gungok-dong.
وكذلك كانت الضحية في جونجوك دونج.
Right?
يمين؟
I'll check out the crime scene.
سوف أتحقق من مسرح الجريمة.
I'm going to the Special Crime Squad.
سأذهب إلى فرقة الجرائم الخاصة.
As published in the news article,
كما نشر في المقال الإخباري
this case had many similarities to Professor Han's case.
هذه الحالة لها أوجه تشابه كثيرة مع قضية البروفيسور هان.
What? Then it wasn't a revenge killing?
ماذا؟ إذن لم يكن قتلاً انتقامياً؟
We'll have to investigate more, but we don't have any suspects...
سيتعين علينا إجراء تحقيقات أكثر، لكن ليس لدينا أي مشتبه بهم...
for Professor Han's killer.
لقاتل البروفيسور هان.
They both died from a blunt force trauma in the head.
كلاهما ماتا متأثرين بصدمة حادة في الرأس.
And it was staged as a robbery?
وتم تنظيمها على أنها سرقة؟
Yes.
نعم.
Gil Pyo. Chief.
جيل بيو. رئيس.
Hey, we're busy. Come back later.
مهلا، نحن مشغولون. أعود لاحقا.
- Check this out now. - Come back later.
- تحقق من هذا الآن. - أعود لاحقا.
Just look at this. They are both hiking shoes.
مجرد إلقاء نظرة على هذا. كلاهما حذاء المشي لمسافات طويلة.
What about them?
ماذا عنهم؟
In Tak brought them to me.
في تاك أحضرهم لي.
One of them is from Suseong-dong. The other one is from Gungok-dong.
واحد منهم من سوسونغ دونغ. والآخر من جونجوك دونج.
Suseong-dong is in Gangnam. And Gungok-dong is in Jongno.
(سوسونج دونج في جانج نام). وGungok-dong موجود في Jongno.
- Give me that. - It's the same guy.
- أعطني ذلك. - إنه نفس الرجل.
I read the reports. It's the same MO.
قرأت التقارير. إنه نفس MO.
- Blunt force trauma? - Yes. Exactly.
- صدمة القوة الحادة؟ - نعم. بالضبط.
Suseong-dong and Gungok-dong...
سوسونغ دونغ وغونغوك دونغ...
They were both hit in the head.
كلاهما أصيبا في الرأس.
The victim in Jinjung-dong also died from blunt force trauma.
كما توفيت الضحية في جينجونغ دونغ متأثرة بصدمة حادة.
You knew?
هل تعلم؟
I just got back...
لقد عدت للتو...
from the crime scene in Jinjung-dong.
من مسرح الجريمة في جينجونغ دونغ.
Who on earth is this guy?
من هو هذا الرجل على وجه الأرض؟
The MO is the same.
مو هو نفسه.
What are you doing here?
ما الذي تفعله هنا؟
Let me in.
اسمحوا لي بالدخول.
You're not an investigator. Why are you here?
أنت لست محققا. لماذا أنت هنا؟
I need to see the crime scene.
أحتاج لرؤية مسرح الجريمة.
Leave!
يترك!
Don't try to steal my case. Get lost!
لا تحاول سرقة قضيتي. اغرب عن وجهي!
Please. I must check the crime scene.
لو سمحت. يجب أن أتحقق من مسرح الجريمة.
Hey. Didn't you hear me? I told you to get lost, you punk!
يا. ألم تسمعني؟ قلت لك أن تضيع، أيها الشرير!
Darn it.
الرتق.
This is important.
هذا مهم.
(Scientific Investigations Team)
(فريق التحقيقات العلمية)
The victim was hit by a blunt instrument.
وتعرض الضحية للضرب بأداة حادة.
(Blunt force trauma in the head)
(صدمة قوية في الرأس)
There are no footsteps in the bedroom.
لا توجد خطى في غرفة النوم.
And the safe wasn't touched either.
ولم يتم لمس الخزنة أيضًا.
(Crime scene stepping plates)
(لوحات دخول مسرح الجريمة)
There's no trace of blood splattered on the ceiling.
لا يوجد أي أثر للدماء متناثرة على السقف.
It means...
يعني...
the culprit subdued the victim with one blow.
قام الجاني بإخضاع الضحية بضربة واحدة.
- Yes. - Are you there?
- نعم. - هل أنت هناك؟
What do we do?
ماذا نفعل؟
I thought we had ten years.
اعتقدت أن لدينا عشر سنوات.
But it happened sooner than I thought.
لكن ذلك حدث في وقت أقرب مما كنت أعتقد.
Everything fits.
كل شيء مناسب.
(A psychological cooling-off period)
(فترة تهدئة نفسية)
(Crime committed against a stranger, for the sole purpose of murder)
(جريمة ترتكب ضد شخص غريب لغرض القتل فقط)
The police admitted that the recent murder cases...
واعترفت الشرطة بأن جرائم القتل الأخيرة...
in the wealthy neighborhood...
في حي الأثرياء..
could have been part of a serial murder.
يمكن أن يكون جزءًا من جريمة قتل تسلسلية.
The police will consider the three murder cases...
وستنظر الشرطة في قضايا القتل الثلاثة...
in Gangnam and Jongno as serial murder cases...
في جانج نام وجونجنو كقضايا قتل متسلسلة...
and do their best to find the culprit quickly...
ويبذلون قصارى جهدهم للعثور على الجاني بسرعة ...
by dispatching more resources in these neighborhoods.
عن طريق إرسال المزيد من الموارد في هذه الأحياء.
There have been murder cases in Suseong-dong...
كانت هناك حالات قتل في سوسونغ دونغ...
and Jinjung-dong, Gangnam-gu back to back.
و Jinjung-dong، Gangnam-gu ظهرًا لظهر.
And between these two cases, a similar murder case...
وبين هاتين الحالتين جريمة قتل مماثلة...
took place in Gungok-dong, Jongno-gu.
وقعت في جونجوك دونج، جونجنو جو.
And the late discovery of the news...
وتأخر اكتشاف الخبر..
has put the residents in fear.
وضعت السكان في حالة من الخوف.
(Do Not Enter, Under Investigation)
(ممنوع الدخول، قيد التحقيق)
Move back.
العودة إلى الوراء.
The culprit went to different neighborhoods...
الجاني ذهب إلى أحياء مختلفة..
and was only after the act of killing.
ولم يكن ذلك إلا بعد فعل القتل.
Three murders.
ثلاث جرائم قتل.
Step back.
تراجع.
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
(Do Not Enter, Under Investigation)
(ممنوع الدخول، قيد التحقيق)
What happened here?
ماذا حدث هنا؟
It's serial murder.
إنها جريمة قتل تسلسلية.
(Through the Darkness)
(عبر الظلام)
A woman in her 60s was found dead...
العثور على امرأة في الستينات من عمرها مقتولة...
in her house in Pyeonghwa-dong. The police are investigating now.
في منزلها في بيونغهوا دونغ. وتقوم الشرطة بالتحقيق الآن.
- A blunt force trauma. - The triangle again?
- صدمة قوية. - المثلث مرة أخرى؟
Something is off. I'm sure he saw something unexpected.
شيء ما معطل. أنا متأكد من أنه رأى شيئا غير متوقع.
Come on, Behavioral Analysis Team. Go back to your office.
هيا، فريق التحليل السلوكي. ارجع إلى مكتبك.
Entering the crime scene as you please...
دخول مسرح الجريمة كما يحلو لك...
is hindering our investigation.
يعيق تحقيقنا.
The answer must be at the crime scene.
الجواب يجب أن يكون في مسرح الجريمة.
What should we do with that?
ماذا يجب أن نفعل مع ذلك؟
We can buy time.
يمكننا شراء الوقت.
I hope you're not buying this nonsense.
آمل أنك لا تشتري هذا الهراء.
The only way to prevent the killer from going after another victim...
الطريقة الوحيدة لمنع القاتل من ملاحقة ضحية أخرى...
is this.
هذا هو.
(Tomorrow at 10pm)
(غدا الساعة 10 مساءا)